Listen, maybe you're like me.
I don't need to be right. It's just that
part of me feels it is a moral failing
if I ever am wrong. Sometimes I feel
people offering a helpful suggestion to
me, and I feel the voice coming up
inside of me. I know, I know that. And
it's like, girly, literally no one's
attacking you. People are actually just
trying to be helpful. So, why are you so
defensive?
Anyway, I decided enough's enough and
this is the year I'm going to be
vulnerable. I was talking to a friend
about this, and she was like, "What if
you just try saying, 'I don't know
anything?'" And I was like, "But I do
know some things." And she's like,
"Listen, it's a spiritual concept. Yes,
of course I believe some things are true
and some things are not. But when I tell
myself I don't know anything, I am
always open to learning something more,
something new. I'm not tied to the
identity of needing to be right or
needing to be the one who knows."
Okay. And it got me thinking, maybe I
feel that knowledge is power, and I use
it and I wear it like armor to make me
feel powerful, to make me feel safe. But
if knowledge is power, if knowledge is
armor, then I'm wearing armor all the
time.
It's impractical. It's heavy, and I
don't know how to take it off, and I
don't know how to let people see me when
I feel stupid. After I wrote this song,
it had me thinking about the time in my
life when I was at my darkest. I felt
that I knew things do not get better.
And what can I say besides I love being
wrong.
>> [music]
>> I'm [music] still [singing] taking my
first
steps.
I'm still [singing] learning to crawl.
>> [music]
>> No such thing as lost progress.
I forgive when I [music] fall.
Used to think I had the answers.
Gave me [singing and music] power and
might.
But there's freedom in learning.
You won't always be right. [singing]
>> [music]
>> If knowledge is power, then I'm choosing
freedom. I don't [music] know a thing,
but I trust, I'm believing. [music] And
it's not a test. It's my first time
living. [music and singing]
I won't do it perfectly.
I'm just beginning.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Wouldn't it be so [music] boring
if I knew it all?
>> [music]
>> If I'm all done with learning,
my world [singing]
would be so [music] small.
I used to be cynical.
[music and singing]
So stubborn and strong.
>> [music]
[singing]
>> Thought I had all the answers.
God, [music and singing] I love being
wrong.
If knowledge is power, then I'm
[music and singing] choosing freedom. I
don't know a thing, but [music] I trust
I'm believing. [singing]
And it's not a test. It's [music] my
first time [singing] living. I won't do
perfectly.
I'm just beginning.
And I'm not a robot. [singing and music]
With sunshine, I am living. I open
[singing and music] my heart to the
parts I'm forgiving.
I don't know a thing, but one thing's
[singing] for certain, [music]
love is the medicine to cure what is
hurting.
>> [music and singing]
[music and singing]
>> I'm learning to open. [music]
I'm letting it go.
The need to be right,
[music and singing]
the need to control.
I loosen [singing] my grip. The story
unfolds. [music] I'm letting love in.
I'm learning to grow.
>> [music]
>> There's still so much I don't know.
[music]
>> If knowledge is power, then I'm choosing
freedom.
I don't know a thing, but I trust, I'm
believing.
It's not [music] a test. It's my first
time living.
I won't do it perfectly.
I'm just beginning.
My [music] life's a temple,
and each day I'm building. I put in the
windows, I'm folding the linens. I don't
[music] know a thing,
but one thing's for certain,
love is the medicine to cure what is
hurting.
Love is the medicine to [music] cure
what is hurting.
Love is the medicine to cure.
>> [music]
>> Anyway,
that's my song.
What do I want to tell you? My name is
Tessa Violet. It's out right now.
If you want to listen to it, and it is
from my new album There Will Be Joy,
which I'm releasing this year, one song
at a time, one month at a time. So, if
you would like to be notified when the
next song comes out, please, there is a
link in the description. And um what
else do I want to say? I'm not wearing
sunscreen, so I got to get out of the
sun. I really feel like I'm get
forgetting something.
Uh
>> Mhm.